Fly on your own. Find your way home.
How to Train Your Dragon: The Hidden World is a animation,
family, adventure film directed by Dean DeBlois.
As Hiccup fulfills his dream of creating a peaceful dragon utopia, Toothless’
discovery of an untamed, elusive mate draws the Night Fury away.
When danger mounts at home and Hiccup’s reign as village chief is tested, both
dragon and rider must make impossible decisions to save their kind.
Hiccup (voice), played by Jay Baruchel.
Astrid (voice), played by America Ferrera.
Grimmel (voice), played by F. Murray Abraham.
Valka (voice), played by Cate Blanchett.
Stoick (voice), played by Gerard Butler.
Gobber (voice), played by Craig Ferguson.
How to Train Your Dragon: The Hidden World is a 2019 American animated fantasy film written and
directed by Dean DeBlois, loosely based on the book series by Cressida Cowell.
Produced by DreamWorks Animation, it is the final
installment in the How to Train Your Dragon trilogy.
The film stars the voices of Jay Baruchel, America Ferrera, F.
Murray Abraham, Cate Blanchett, Gerard Butler, Craig Ferguson, Jonah Hill,
Christopher Mintz-Plasse, Kristen Wiig, and Kit Harington.
The film follows 21-year-old Hiccup seeking a dragon utopia known as the "Hidden World" while coming to terms with
Toothless's new bond with a female Fury, as they deal with the threat of Grimmel the Grisly, a ruthless dragon hunter.
Discussions regarding a third How to Train Your Dragon film began in December 2010, with DeBlois later
stating that the second film was being intentionally designed as the second act of a trilogy.
The animation challenges of the production required DreamWorks Animation to update and invent
new software to handle complex tasks, such as lighting the Light Fury dragon.
How to Train Your Dragon: The Hidden World was released in Australia on January 3,
2019, and in the United States by Universal Pictures on February 22.
Like its predecessors, it received critical acclaim, with reviewers considering it a satisfying
conclusion to the trilogy, with praise for the animation and its emotional weight.
The film grossed $540 million, and received several accolades, including five Annie Awards nominations, a
Golden Globe nomination, and a nomination for Best Animated Feature at the 92nd Academy Awards.
The film explores themes of based on novel or book,
flying, affectation, villain, melancholy.
The tone is lighthearted and thought_provoking and intense.